Guide to the Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot, 1200-2003 (bulk1900-2003)
Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot 1200-2003 (bulk 1900-2003
- Purpose List Series, 1200-2003
  - Kibbutz Subseries, 1937-1979, (44 items)
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1958., 17 x 25 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1958-1959., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 195-?., 20 cm. Illustrated.
      Handwritten and Illustrated by David Alef. Non-traditional text. Duke owns two copies of this Haggadah.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 195-?., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 22 cm. Text only.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 197-?., 27 x 13 cm. Illustrated.
  - Military Subseries, 1918-1971, (15 items)
    Used by military personnel, including the Israeli military during the 1948 War of Independence (Haggadah Pam #14); American military from World War I (Haggadah Pam 12mo #30); and Jewish soldiers in Berlin immediately following the end of World War II (Haggadah Pam #53).
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Seder service for Passover eve in the home / arranged by Mrs. Philip Cowen, 1918., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Order of service for Passover (Haggada) / issued by the Jewish War Services Committee for India, 1918., 19 cm. Text only.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah (The Cowen Haggadah) = The Seder service for Passover eve in the home / arranged by Mrs. Philip Cowen, 1935., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah (The Cowen Haggadah) = The Seder service for Passover eve in the home / arranged by Mrs. Philip Cowen, 1935., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = Haggadah of Passover: prepared for use of Jewish personnel of the Army and Navy of the United States in French North Africa during the Passover of the year 5703 .., 1943., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Haggadah of Passover / edited by David and Tamar de Sola Pool for members of the armed forces of the United States, 1945., 19 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Seder service: Deutsches Theatre Restaurant, Munich, Germany, April 15-16, 1946 / conducting, Abraham J. Klausner, 1945-1946., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Le-hag ha-herut 708, 1948., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1949-1950., 22 cm. Illustrated.
    - Le-hag ha herut: perakim, 1949-1950., 24 cm. Illustrated.
    - Passover Korea, 1952, 1952?., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Passover Haggadah: for Jewish personnel in the U.S. Armed Forces and Veterans Administration hospitals, 1952., 18 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel ha-Seneh le-Pesah, 195-?., 16 x 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = The Haggadah of Passover / edited by Rabbi David and Tamar de Sola Pool, 1963., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Passover Haggadah / edited by David Jay Derovan and Moshe Berliner; illustrated by Daniel Derovan, 1978., 28 cm. Text only.
  - Parody Subseries, 1817, 1849, (2 items)
    Parodies of the Passover Haggadah. Includes a Haggadah for Purim (Haggadah Pam #3) that focuses on the drunken revelry of Purim and includes its own version of the four sons, one of whom Does not even know how to drink in imitation of the Passover Haggadah's son who Does not even know how to ask.
    - Agadat arba' Kosot, 1817., 18 cm. Text only.
    - Hagadah le-lel shikorim, 1849., 19 cm. Text only.
  - Resource Subseries, 1949-2002, (18 items)
    Contains books about Haggadot, useful as research aids for finding and learning about different types, as well as specific editions, of Haggadot.
    - Bibliographie der Oster-Haggadah, 1500-1900 / von S. Wiener, 1949., 29 cm. Text only.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1960., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., 35 cm. Illustrated.
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., 35 cm. Illustrated.
    - The John Rylands Haggadah / Cecil Roth, 1960., 25 cm. Resource Material.
    - Ta`arukhat Hagadot-Pesh me-osfo R. Natan Stayner .., 1964., 17 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Haggadah: past and present, 1965., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah and woodcut: an introduction to the Passover Haggadah completed by Gershom Cohen in Prague, Sunday, 26 Teveth, 5287--Dec. 30, 1526 / by Rabbi Charles Wengrov, 1967., 29 cm. Illustrated.
    - Exhibit: Haggadahs and Passover ceremonial art, April-June, 1970, 1970., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah and history: a panorama in facsimile of five centuries of the printed Haggadah from the collections of Harvard University and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America / by Yosef Hayim Yerushalmi, 1975., Illustrated.
    - Haggadah and history: a panorama in facsimile of five centuries of the printed Haggadah from the collections of Harvard University and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America / by Yosef Hayim Yerushalmi, 1975., Illustrated.
    - ha-Metsayer bi-yetsi'at Mitsrayim: Hagadot metsuyarot min ha-me'ah ha-18 / [mehkar ve-tekst, Havivah Peled-Karmeli; `arikhah, Yonah Fisher], 1983., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - ha-Metsayer bi-yetsi'at Mitsrayim: Hagadot metsuyarot min ha-me'ah ha-18 / [mehkar ve-tekst, Havivah Peled-Karmeli; `arikhah, Yonah Fisher], 1983., 27 cm. Illustrated.
    - The Sarajevo Haggadah / Eugen Werber; [translation, Olga Popovic-Marjanovic], 1983., 23 cm. Text only.
    - Collector's Haggadah catalogue, 1695-present, 1994., 28 cm. Illustrated.
    - Otsar ha-hagadot: bibliyografyah shel hagadot Pesah me-reshit ha-defus ha-`Ivri `ad shenat 720 / ba-`arikhat Yitshak Yudlov, 1997., 35 cm. Text only.
    - Otsar ha-hagadot: bibliyografyah shel hagadot Pesah me-reshit ha-defus ha-`Ivri `ad shenat 720 / ba-`arikhat Yitshak Yudlov, 1997., 35 cm. Text only.
    - Let my people go: insights to Passover and the Haggadah / Jeffrey M. Cohen, 2002., 23 cm. Text only.